RAYMOND ORTIZ

A High School Football Coach with six years of experience delivering coaching and mentorship to student-athletes to nurture talent and drive personal growth. A strong history of buildin g inclusive team cu Itures a nd u tilizing a wide ra nge of coaching styles.

Philadelphia, PA 12345
ray mo n d o rtiz@exa m ple.com
(123) 456-7890
Linked In | Portfolio

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

HEAD FOOTBALL COACH

Lowell High School, Lowell, CA May 2019-Present

- Serve as the head football coach for the Lowell Knights Football Team, develop
 offensive and defensive game plans, nurture talent and growth, and achieve Valley
 Big 12 League Conference Titles in 2021 and 2022
- Deliver coaching and mentorship to support student performance on the field and academically, contributing to a 98% graduation rate among football student-athletes
- ♦ Achieve a record of 51-9 from 2016-2022 with a winning percentage of 83.35%

ASSISTANT FOOTBALL COACH

Mission High School, San Francisco, CA June 2017- May 2019

- Collaborated with the head coach and assistants to create an inclusive football program and team culture, which supported academic, personal, and athletic growth for students
- Managed and developed practice drills for defensive players in the secondary to achieve an average turnover rate of two per game during the 2015 season
- Monitored fitness training and practice regimens, encouraged healthy nutrition, and ensured compliance with player safety protocols to prevent injuries

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science (B.S.) Sports Management

University of San Francisco, San Francisco, CA September 2013 - June 2017

KEY SKILLS

- ♦ Football Coaching
- ♦ Sports Science
- Student Mentorship
- ♦ Athlete Development
- ♦ Physical Education

CERTIFICATIONS

- ♦ First Aid Certified, Red Cross, 2017
- ◆ Basic Life Su p port (B LS), America n Heart Association, 2017